## **Benjamin Grinthal**

#### CONTACT

**Address**: 9206 Morgan Way, Mount Laurel NJ,

**Phone**: (732) 616-8142

08054

Email: bgrinthal@gmail.-

com

#### **SKILLS**

- Computer-Aided Design (CAD)
- MATLAB
- SolidWorks / AutoCAD
- Microsoft Visio
- Management and delegation
- 3D Modeling/ Design
- Product Development
- Mechanical Design
- Teamwork/ Collaboration
- Manufacturing Process
- JavaScript, HTML5, CSS
- Bootstrap
- JQuery
- Express.js, Node.js
- Git, Heroku
- Object Oriented Programming
- MySQL
- React

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Determined mechanical engineering with over 6 years of experience. Seeking to use proven design, problem-solving, and management skills to excel any position. Collaborative team player with track record of delivering multiple, concurrent projects in fast-paced environments.

#### **RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

### Rutgers Coding Bootcamp Certification 05/2022 to 08/2022

Full Stack Developer - New Brunswick, NJ

- 3 month intensive course in a variety of programming languages and technologies
- Created a diverse portfolio in group and solo projects to design reactive front and back end applications deployed on GitHub. Some examples include:

<u>Password Generator</u>: JavaScript application to take user input of desired characters to be used and returns randomized sequence of the selected characters

<u>Weather Tracker</u>: Uses API's and takes in city names to display popular weather information in a the area for the coming week

<u>Team Profile Generator</u>: A Node.js command line application to build then display a professional team using object oriented programing

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### **OSP Engineer** 11/2021 to 04/2022

Verizon - Mount Laurel, NJ

- Managed the damage, upgrade, and installation of Verizon's facilities in designated areas
- Coordinate with construction, power companies, and project managers to ensure work is completed in a timely manner
- Work with vendors to increase production and create accurate design for construction to follow
- Represent Verizon in meetings and surveys to solve problems or to expand the network into new locations

#### **Design Engineer,** 04/2018 to 11/2021

#### Byers Engineering Company Inc. - Somerset, NJ

- Design layouts for Verizon's service providing cables through large New York City streets and buildings
- Create CAD drawings using Microsoft Visio and AutoCAD to convey manufacturing and production configurations
- Estimate quantities and cost of materials, equipment, and labor to determine project feasibility
- Develop proposals for clients outlining project scope and timeline
- Provide technical guidance, peer review, and mentorship to junior engineers engaged in Fios building designs
- Read and interpret blueprints, technical drawings, schematics, and computer-generated reports
- Travels to location to sketch/verify on field information to use for design

# **Design Engineer Intern,** 06/2011 to 12/2016 **RotorClip Company** - Somerset, NJ

- Perform tolerance analysis to support success in high-volume heat treatment product manufacturing
- Operate tensile and hardness testing machines to perform spot analysis on products
- Use Solidworks to design tools for creating company retaining rings
- Design retaining rings meeting company and customer tolerance and material standards
- Document drawing edits using Engineering Change Notices (ECN)

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science : Mechanical Engineering, 05/2016 Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey - New Brunswick, NJ

Aerospace Engineering Certificate